Nick Bowman: Alright, so let's go ahead and get started.
Nick Bowman: Alright, so the slides are
Nick Bowman: Okay, there we go. Alright, so let's get started. So today we are going to be talking about and sort of taking the next step in our journey recursion and really
Nick Bowman: Thoroughly exploring this idea of reverse of backtracking. And so today's question and is think of some games that you play. You can be sort of any type of game.
Nick Bowman: What is an example of a game in be able to be really good at sort of quickly. Think of all possible moves of ways that you could
Nick Bowman: That you could potentially take
Nick Bowman: And. Cool. So like I said, we're going to be staying in the land of the first of problem solving today and sort of extending our exploration of a person backtracking.
Nick Bowman: And today's questions going to be how can you leverage the person backtracking to solve interesting problems.
Nick Bowman: And to do that we're going to do a little bit of review of the definition of recursive backtracking from yesterday.
Nick Bowman: And we're going to talk about a game called word scramble and we're going to talk about a class of words called drinkable words and we're going to finish off by talking about these things called subsets at the very end of class get generated
Nick Bowman: And so there are you today. So we saw some more advanced repairs and patterns and yesterday lecture.
Nick Bowman: And these advanced recursion patterns answered us are allowed us to start answering the question why we use recursion.
Nick Bowman: So we saw that there's elegance and recursion, we could solve solve problems with very clean and concise code, especially compared to other solutions.
Nick Bowman: We saw the recursion could allow us to gain get really good games and efficiency and by dividing our problem space up into much smaller versions of the problem.
Nick Bowman: And we saw that incursion could be dynamic and lessons that could allow us to solve problems are very hard to solve effectively and that'll be the main focus of what we use recruiting for today.
Nick Bowman: So our elegance example was the towers of paranoia and so we saw this idea that with recursion, we could solve the towers of Hanoi in about five lines of code.
Nick Bowman: And with iteration to take about like 5050 but it took a lot, right. It was a lot less sort of intuitive about what the solution would look like.
Nick Bowman: And then we saw with binary search this idea of getting really good efficiency and sort of a new runtime that we haven't encountered before called logarithmic runtime.
Nick Bowman: And binary search was specifically a great example of a what's called a divide and conquer algorithm where
Nick Bowman: By eliminating a large portion of our search space at the time by leveraging structure in the data. We were able to sort of get this
Nick Bowman: Logarithmic behavior where our runtime increases very, very slowly as our input size increases and still it still increases, but it just increases at a much lower.
Nick Bowman: Rate than we would see with a linear algorithm and resolve this example of just how much more powerful binary search was as compared to linear search
Nick Bowman: And so, you know, it's about like you can see the, the way that you can get up to 64 million items searched in the binary search and about the same amount of time to tell it takes to do 20,000 linear search just kind of just a crazy fast. Speed up.
Nick Bowman: And and then we saw the dynamic nature of reference. We talked about decision trees and
Nick Bowman: This idea that we can sort of think about this idea of exploring all possible reality is all possible ways. It's something that happened.
Nick Bowman: And illustrate this process using sort of the branching tree like nature of recursion, where we have sort of number of decisions that define our branches. At every given point in time.
Nick Bowman: And and then to sort of exhaustively explore all possible options we try every possible option for every possible decision.
Nick Bowman: And this is going to be a really common theme of what we see today.
Nick Bowman: And then last thing that we saw was this just idea of the two different types of recursion.
Nick Bowman: And so we started the week by talking about or refer to as basic recursion. So we had sort of one repeated task we built up a solution and using information stored in the call stack.
Nick Bowman: And usually the final base case would give us sort of initial seed of our solution and we build up that solution as we worked our way back out through the call stack.
Nick Bowman: And but then yesterday, we introduced this new idea of recursion, which is called backtracking recursion, where we use the tree like branching structure recursion to build up as many possible solutions as we can.
Nick Bowman: And we have multiple recursive calls at each step. And we usually start off with an empty solution and we build up that solution and rebuild many different possible solutions at once. As we work our way down the tree.
Nick Bowman: And then once we get to the base cases we're actually able to determine exactly where solutions are there.
Nick Bowman: And so the question is for today is how can we leverage this whole second class of recursive, problem solving, to actually start solving interesting problems.
Nick Bowman: And there's kind of three main categories of problems that we're going to think about and that we can solve with backtracking.
Nick Bowman: One we've seen already with yesterday's heads, tails sort of coin sequences problem which is generating sort of all possible solutions or all possible ways that something had happened.
Nick Bowman: Or just counting the number of possible ways that something can happen. And we can also find one specific solution to a problem or prove that one exists. And you see that today.
Nick Bowman: And then we can also find the best possible solution to a given problem. One nice thing about the fact that we're looking at all possible solutions along the way is you can actually find one that's categorized as, quote unquote, the best
Nick Bowman: And and sort of use that as a as an application recursion.
Nick Bowman: Within each of these categories. There's lots of different possible meanings to like the problems that you're solving
Nick Bowman: So the problems that you're solving can involve generating permutations generating subsets generating combinations will define what each of these things are
Nick Bowman: And we get a lot more specific specifically and permutations and subsets today.
Nick Bowman: But there you can think of, sort of, you want you when you're solving a backtracking problem you saw in pick one from party and you pick one from party.
Nick Bowman: In terms of, you know, you pick the kind of problem you're going to solve. And you also pick how you're going to solve, you know, find all the solutions. Just one. The next one, and things like that.
Nick Bowman: And so specifically. Today we're going to talk about generating all possible solutions to a problem and it's going to be this idea or recall enumeration.
Nick Bowman: And we're also going to talk a little bit about finding one specific solution to a problem and how that is similar to and different from this idea of integration.
Nick Bowman: And in terms of the specific problems that we're going to solve. We're going to look at Turner and permutations, which will be the first half of the lecture commemorating subsets, which will be the second
Nick Bowman: So let's talk about, let's talk about a game usually like to try to define new concepts in terms of things that you can play
Nick Bowman: So some of you probably encountered this before.
Nick Bowman: It's a game called john logos, but a lot of different names, but it's a it's a word puzzle that's been in newspapers for a really long time.
Nick Bowman: The basic idea is you're just given a sequence of scrambled letters and you need to unscramble those letters to fill in.
Nick Bowman: The empty boxes and then after you've done that, once then you get a bunch of circled letters which are again scrambled. And then you unscramble those to answer the planet.
Nick Bowman: And so, for this example, I'm not going to go over it and super detail, but you'd see that you first unscramble the words on the left, then you will get your circle letters and your unscrambled right and you get sort of the answer. It does come come back.
Nick Bowman: And. And if you think about, you know, playing this game are solving this puzzle and you know for some people might come pretty easily. You know, if you have a
Nick Bowman: Big vocabulary feel comfortable sort of arranging these things in your head. And maybe you can solve it easily. But it's not an easy puzzle to solve just even for like a six letter word like
Nick Bowman: Of course, when you're given car. Oh, and he
Nick Bowman: And there's actually n factorial murder that he comes back into play. There's actually six factorial, which is 720 different ways that you could arrange those letters.
Nick Bowman: And so technically finding the solution might require through looking through a large portion of those different events in order to find the word that you want.
Nick Bowman: And so we're going to ask ourselves can we write a program to actually help us do this sort of sort of print out all of the possible ways that we can arrange
Nick Bowman: These letters in order to help us solve this puzzle.
Nick Bowman: An order to do. We're going to talk about this idea of permutations and a permutation of a sequence is basically just the elements of that sequence.
Nick Bowman: And in any order. So either in the original order or in different order. And you can see an example of that. So you have the Moto
Nick Bowman: E Pluribus Unum right and you can take the permutations of the words in that motto.
Nick Bowman: And and if you arrange that these words in different orders, you can actually get six different ways of having the words in this model arranged
Nick Bowman: And so the key component of a permutation is you have to use everything from your original collection of your original sequence of objects.
Nick Bowman: And then you can put them into either the exact same order or any different possible order.
Nick Bowman: And obviously the tie back to our word game is if we think about solving the puzzle. You're going to need to generate many different possible permutations of the letters that you're given in order to find the correct word
Nick Bowman: And they're always guarantee that there's one, there's only one correct English word that comes out.
Nick Bowman: And tying back to what we saw yesterday permutations are actually relatively similar to the coin flip sequences that are generally yesterday.
Nick Bowman: In the sense that it's just a sequence, you're generating a sequence of objects. The order in which you put them matters, right. So we cared about sort of the order in which we were building of the solutions.
Nick Bowman: But the key difference is that rather than having to fixed options at every single point in time right you with the coin flips, you can always put the heads or you can always flip the tables. We always have one of those two options.
Nick Bowman: The components of our original sequence actually defined the options that we have to build our new sequence. So we don't have an unlimited number of
Nick Bowman: Options. Right. We always have a sort of constraints that have options. And that number of options might change over time as we use elements from original see
Nick Bowman: And so before we go any further with this sort of what we want to do for for breakout rooms today and is we're going to give you sort of the detox.
Nick Bowman: Really only the first two, we expect you have time to get to. But if you do have time to get to the third. That'll be helpful to discuss and
Nick Bowman: And so the first is with your roommates. Just try to come up with all the permutations of the string Saki
Nick Bowman: In this case, the elements of the string or the character so you'll be rearranging characters to get these permutations
Nick Bowman: And just try to try to figure out if you can find them all as a hint there should be 24 of them. So there's four elements. There's four characters in the string Saki there's always for factorial permutations of something and for factorial is equal to try
Nick Bowman: To see if you can generate them all and then after you've generated them or even if you're partway through generating
Nick Bowman: And thinking about what potential recursive insights you could make to go to glean about generalities permutations and can you figure out why might this be a good problem to solve, or personally
Nick Bowman: And think to, yes. Think back to yesterday's sequences example and so is there a way that you can leverage sort of what we saw there.
Nick Bowman: Yeah, let's go ahead and send you guys off the breakout rooms will bring you back in about three to four.
Nick Bowman: And then for those of you watching asynchronously.
Nick Bowman: I can recommend pausing here if you go on over to the other workspace on a little bit of scratch area that you can use on today down your permutations and then she write about your
Nick Bowman: Your recursive insights and when working through this problem.
Nick Bowman: And then, yeah, then fast forward to about two and a half minutes from now one more. I'm gonna bring it
Nick Bowman: And so let's go ahead and sort of see if you can summarize what hopefully you all talked about in your breakout rooms.
Nick Bowman: But actually, before I do that, I want to answer. A common question that actually came up during lecture yesterday.
Nick Bowman: And which were we got a lot of questions about, oh, well, all of these problems that were saying, or like we're going to solve the Caribbean coast engine better, cleaner.
Nick Bowman: And do they have equivalent innovative solutions. And so you might have a question or why did I asked you to think about these permutations and personally rather than, you know, maybe thinking intuitive way to generate them.
Nick Bowman: And the answer is, okay, well, here's a solution to it or to regenerate permutations of a four letter string.
Nick Bowman: And you need a for loop for every possible index. Right. So you need to you need to try all options for the first character all options for the second character all options for third
Nick Bowman: And so you would need a for loop for every character. Well, if you wanted to generate permutations for a five letter string, you'd have to add another For Loop.
Nick Bowman: Right and curator for six, you have to add another four luqman you have six nested for loops and the really the point here is this is kind of horrifying.
Nick Bowman: You do not want to sort of be approaching generating the permutations in this way. And so even though the integrated solutions do exist and they are unfortunately are not big break their, their small bring
Nick Bowman: solutions to this problem. And so recursion here really tier is going to kind of be the key.
Nick Bowman: So let's see if we can get some intuition. So here's all the all the permutations of the string Saki. I'm not going to go through them individually, but here they are.
Nick Bowman: And I've arranged live in a certain way because I want you all to see a pattern. And what is this pattern. Well, according to these permutations, start with the letter S.
Nick Bowman: And then if you look at their remaining letters among among the six examples. It's just permutations of the letters AK
Nick Bowman: And a quarter the permutations. Start with a and then they followed by permutations of the sky and I
Nick Bowman: Have a quarter of them start with k and then there follow it with permutations of a and I, and then a quarter of them start with I. And then followed by all the different possible permutations of SDN
Nick Bowman: And and so can we formalize this intuition decision tree is it can we actually use this insight about always possible permutations to start thinking about how we define the decision tree for this problem.
Nick Bowman: And so let's think about what actually might define this. So when we have a decision tree right if you remember from yesterday, we always have a decision that we need to make at each step.
Nick Bowman: And and so the decision in this case, we noticed. Okay, well, all of the possible letters were used a starting letter. So we had some that serve as some that started with K some sort of a sudden started with high
Nick Bowman: And and so the decision that we need to make when we're building up any given permutation is what is the next letter that we're going to add to it. What is the letter that it's going to start with, or what's the letter that's going to be second or third or fourth with things like that.
Nick Bowman: And then when we're making that decision where our branch and comes into play, is the fact that we have different options for those decisions. So we actually have one option for every remaining element that we haven't used up yet.
Nick Bowman: Right and and what's different about this as compared to our previous example is that we actually got a different number of options at each level of the tree.
Nick Bowman: And what does that mean well that means that initially we have four letter to choose from. But then after we choose one, we only have three and then the two that we only have one and so on.
Nick Bowman: And so the information that we need to keep track of as we go through this is both the permutation, we built so far so that we can make our decision and add something on us onto it.
Nick Bowman: And also the remaining elements that we have left because the remaining elements that we have left from our original sequence defines the options that we have
Nick Bowman: And so let's try to draw this decision tree. And so we're going to use sort of a color coded scheme here.
Nick Bowman: Like we just said we're going to keep track of two pieces of information at each level.
Nick Bowman: And we're going to have keep track of the decisions that we haven't made yet. So our remaining options and then the red and that's gonna be represented and blue. And then in the red. We're going to have
Nick Bowman: The permutation that we've built up so far. And so we're going to try to find out permutations of the work. And so if we follow our idea from the previous step.
Nick Bowman: The first decision and the first option we could solve because we can say okay let's decide to include the letter C or petition. So let's make up the next letter that we have
Nick Bowman: And so our remaining letters now goes from ca T to just the letters empty, but our permutation now begins with letter C.
Nick Bowman: And then we can do equivalent things for the remaining letters, right, we could choose to use the letter A first and then we remove that from our meeting options and then insert that into our fermentation
Nick Bowman: Or we could choose to use the letter T first. And so there's actually three branching points from the original of the tree rather started one for the letter C one for the letter A and 130
Nick Bowman: And then we just repeat this process. So now over here on the left hand side.
Nick Bowman: We only have two remaining option. So our decision now becomes, what do we add as the second letter.
Nick Bowman: But we only have two options of what out of the second letter so we could choose to add a or choose and the team. And that gives us sort of branching to to new different possibilities.
Nick Bowman: And similarly for the other decisions, you know, over here, we could choose to add a C or at a tea and then at the at the right hand side, we could choose to add a C or as a as a separate letter.
Nick Bowman: And so now we've generated all possibilities for the first letter, combined with all possibilities for the second letter.
Nick Bowman: Then the very last step that we have to do is we have one option remaining so we kind of just have to take it. We don't really have anything else.
Nick Bowman: And now we've run out of possible things to select from. And we get our final presentation. So actually, our first permutation. The word cat is just the word count, which is totally fine.
Nick Bowman: And then over here we choose a is the last letter and you can just repeat this process for all of the remaining places in the tree.
Nick Bowman: And what you see here we have our decision tree each of our branching points corresponds to the decisions the decisions that we make at every step, and by the power of this branch and we're able to generate all possible options for the permutations of this original work.
Nick Bowman: And then the. So after you've drawn your decision tree. Now's a great time is actually start formalizing the recursive intuition. And in this case, we see that the base case is if there's no letters left to choose.
Nick Bowman: And we see that the recursive case is for every single remaining letter right we add that letter to the current permutation and then we reverse we just continue our decision tree.
Nick Bowman: And so at the very beginning we had three letters or meaning CMT so we branched off three times.
Nick Bowman: And then we got to the second level, we only had two options or meetings we branched off twice and then at the last level, we only have one option remaining so we only have one one possible way.
Nick Bowman: And so let's go ahead and try to actually take that intuition into cutie crater and let's actually try to put this up.
Nick Bowman: And so we're going to be writing this function called list permutations and the goal of this function is just given some string s and can you print out to the console all possible permutations of the characters that exists within that screen.
Nick Bowman: Yes.
Nick Bowman: There we go.
Nick Bowman: And so again, when we go to do this recursion. Right. One of the most important things that we have to keep track of is what information do we need when solving this problem.
Nick Bowman: And if you remember from our decision tree. If I put this back really quick right there was always two pieces of information that we needed at each point we needed the options that we had left and the permutation of your building up so far.
Nick Bowman: And if we look at the function that were asked to implement it doesn't seem like we have that information, right, we only have one piece of information.
Nick Bowman: And so if you ever run into whenever you run into this sort of mismatch between what you know you need to solve the problem.
Nick Bowman: And what the function provided functional prototype is giving you. That's always a good time to sort of bring in this idea of a helper function.
Nick Bowman: And so will say actually word need a function that looks like this. We need one that takes those parameters the string remeeting and the string of things that we've chosen so far and
Nick Bowman: And then, and in order to actually solve our original problem, we'll just say, let's call our helper function.
Nick Bowman: The original set of remaining letters is just the screen. We started with. And then our permutation to begin with is just the empty string.
Nick Bowman: And so this is a super common pattern. As always, don't forget to take a look here.
Nick Bowman: This is a super common pattern we saw it yesterday we were generating the coin sequences. We're going to see it again for all of our examples later today.
Nick Bowman: So really get familiar to this idea of after you've done your decision tree and you know which information you need to keep track of you, you probably will have to add a helper function in order to keep track of all of it.
Nick Bowman: And thought. And so now we can divide it into our base case and our recursive case.
Nick Bowman: And so our base case. In this case, remember we said, All right, well, if we didn't have any more options to choose from. Then we could just go ahead and print out the temptation. If unreal it so far.
Nick Bowman: So that was when we were at the leaves of the tree. So down here with these final actual goal primitive individually.
Nick Bowman: And then the recursive Chase.
Nick Bowman: What are the recursive case. Tell us. Well, the recursive case told us this. It basically said we need to try out all possible options that we have that are right and so we are going to again see this idea of iteration, combined with recursion and
Nick Bowman: And we're going to have to try out all possible things that we have left.
Nick Bowman: And just for purposes of naming of all this.
Nick Bowman: All this option will be a string or the character in the string of looking at right now.
Nick Bowman: And then what do we do, well, we have to update our
Nick Bowman: options that are remaining after we make this decision, right. So that requires removing actually a letter from our current or meeting stream.
Nick Bowman: And so what we can do. We can make a new string. That's all right. It's just going to be everything but the character.
Nick Bowman: Index, I have this way of removing characters with sub string, there's something that you saw actually on the last assignment.
Nick Bowman: Or maybe on the first assignment and it's basically just saying, Take two sub strings and between those two sub streams. There will together sort of combine to eliminate the character index on
Nick Bowman: And then come sort of the boundary of apart the magic of art, which basically just says, in order to generate all the rest of my permutations
Nick Bowman: I'm going to say, all right, this is the decisions. These are the options I have left. And the thing that I've actually done to make progress is I've changed my so far string by adding on the current option.
Nick Bowman: And so that is the recursive call. Notice that we make one recursive call for every iteration of the number of iterations of our loop is equal to the number of
Nick Bowman: And so, yeah. Oh.
Nick Bowman: It didn't, the number of iterations of this is what, sorry, the number of iterations of the loop is the number of recursive called that we have. And so that is the
Nick Bowman: That is the branching factor in our tree, right. So when we have three characters remaining we make sure your cursor calls we have two characters are meeting a few rehearsal halls and so on.
Nick Bowman: And so if we
Nick Bowman: Have this hopefully and what we'll see come up and is just a little console program that shows us all the possible
Nick Bowman: Options that
Nick Bowman: Well, this is also pulling up and let me go ahead and show you the code on the slides and then I have a couple of annotations and different things up and oh that's
Nick Bowman: Okay. And so this is the code that we just wrote hopefully it'll come up with a with a show proof that we actually did it correctly.
Nick Bowman: And but here's the code that we wrote and we use a recursive hopper function with an empty string as a starting point. That's a, that's a key component of recursive backtracking, which is this idea that you can always start off with an empty solution and you build it up over time.
Nick Bowman: And other important things we had two pieces of information, one to store the decisions that we haven't yet me into the decisions we needed to make in the future for the options that we had for future decisions.
Nick Bowman: And then we had a string to keep track of the decisions that we've made so far. And so that would sort of allow us to keep track of our solution over time.
Nick Bowman: We had a base case which said that when there is no decisions left. We know reached a solution and we had a recursive case that said try all possible options for our next decision.
Nick Bowman: And and so the reason I wanted to add these annotations is to show you that you know permutations, a specific example of a problem you can solve the curse of backtracking.
Nick Bowman: And what the patterns that you see when it comes to generating permutations apply more generally to anything that you can express in the decision tree.
Nick Bowman: Once you're able to express your problem in the context of decision tree, you can generate the code by making sure that your parameters for all the options are for all the pieces of information TV.
Nick Bowman: You have a base case that corresponds when you don't have any decisions to make, and you have a recursive case that involves trying all possible options for your next decision.
Nick Bowman: And that will be sort of either the generalization and Well finally, after all that time our little console window popped up and it shows us that we do in the all the permutations that we have on our original slide.
Nick Bowman: And you'll notice. And you might ask, why did I arrange them in that order before. Well, it's actually the order in which they're generated by this decision tree and
Nick Bowman: And so I encourage you to actually think about entries through the decision tree and think about why the permutations actually generated
Nick Bowman: Cool. So what are our final takeaways here. So remember we introduced this terminology of choose explore untruth yesterday when it came to backtrack new version.
Nick Bowman: And and what we saw in this problem was actually the specific idea where we pass all our parameters by the value. And so really what we were doing with this idea of copy edit for
Nick Bowman: Every function call. Every recursive function call gets a copy of all the values that it gets of parameters and then we edit those values in some way. So in this case of involved paring down the recursive or the remaining options that we had. And then we repurpose on our newly updated.
Nick Bowman: Since we pass these parameters by value every stack frame or every function call can edit those values. However, it sees fit.
Nick Bowman: And there actually is no explicit untrue steps. So the untrue step is implicit in the sense that we don't actually need to undo anything before our function finishes, because everything that it was doing all the edits that it was making only have consequences.
Nick Bowman: Sort of locally in that regard.
Nick Bowman: And another important takeaway. And we always had to keep track of the decisions we made so far and the decisions we have left to make that's going to be a very common pattern when it comes to solving reverse of backtracking problems.
Nick Bowman: And and backtracking recursion can actually have variable branching factors. So this was the first time we saw a tree where the number of recursive calls, and the number of branches that we had was different. At every point in time.
Nick Bowman: And this level this when we say that backtracking is dynamic. This is really the greatest example we have how dynamic recursion is
Nick Bowman: Is they can make a variable number of decision or you can, it can explore a variable number of possible options at every step in the process, which is a really cool sort of component
Nick Bowman: Cool. And so that was our sort of first exposure to permutations and and now we're going to revisit a problem that's relatively similar permutations, but helps us solve another interesting word puzzle, which is this idea of shrink bubble or
Nick Bowman: And this idea of drinkable words allows us to answer this question of what not letter word can be reduced to a single letter word one letter at a time, just by removing letters at every step and leaving the word sort of to be illegal word at every step along the way.
Nick Bowman: And the answer is actually startling. So, you know, you can follow this pattern and show that you can actually remove a letter from startling one letter at a time, and every step along the way is actually a valid valid warning.
Nick Bowman: And the question is, well, is there really just one letter, one letter word of this property and how would we actually determine if a word has this property.
Nick Bowman: And so let's see how we might determine this so sure. What word is defined as any word that can be reduced by one letter at a time, leaving a word every step along the way.
Nick Bowman: And the fact that we can potentially remove any one of the different letters at different points in time should get sort of those alarm bells ringing in our head, hey, this might be a really good problem to model using a decision tree. So let's do that.
Nick Bowman: And let's see what made the final decision tree here. And so in this case will say, All right, well, our decision at every step is going to be what letter, we're going to remove and
Nick Bowman: The options again will be will be very every single time, whatever the remaining letters that we have left those will pop
Nick Bowman: Up.
kylie jue: Okay hold on one second. We had tried drop
kylie jue: It so connected
kylie jue: It's not
kylie jue: To ATT said I'm because I'm still connected and I'm wanting to
Know, well, that's fine. That's
kylie jue: Okay. Give us one second, we are attempting to rejoin Nick is also frozen for me.
kylie jue: stop sharing the slides.
Okay. Yes, yes.
kylie jue: Yeah, there were some good questions in the chat while we're waiting for Nick to join, but I'll just reiterate out loud. So it's on the recording and so others here as well.
kylie jue: But really thinking about how do we actually decide what's in the helper function like how do we decide when do we want to help her function. And what are we going to put into it.
kylie jue: Often will give you a function prototype and say this is the function, you need to implement and if it doesn't already have information that you need to keep track of as part of its parameters. That's when you want to have
kylie jue: An additional helper function and think about what parameters. Do I need to actually add to keep track of the information I need as I continue down this tree.
kylie jue: Alright, it looks like Nick's back
kylie jue: I can't, I don't hear
Nick Bowman: You go
Nick Bowman: Okay, cool.
Nick Bowman: Alright, so sorry about that dropped out and how to introduce me. Um, but yeah. So what we were talking about is basically what define
kylie jue: You want to do it.
kylie jue: Oh my god. Okay. Okay. Yeah, I'll leave, I'll leave my mic on and take out my head.
kylie jue: Um, I can hear myself talking. So I'm going to assume that the rest of you can hear me as well as maybe over here, but
kylie jue: We do what we need to do so and so we were talking about are treatable decision tree. And we had this idea that
kylie jue: We're going to need to decide which letter move at every point in time we have these possible options of whatever letters are left to remove. And interestingly enough, the only information that we actually need to store along the way is this shrinking stream.
kylie jue: And so that's sort of an interesting observation.
kylie jue: And so let's try to define what this decision tree looks like.
kylie jue: And so you can see sort of and we're not going to go step by step you're generating this. But what you can see as we if we start off with the word part
kylie jue: We then to generate the first level of our decision tree. Consider first removing the seat like this art we consider removing the A like is a CRT we consider moving the art which gives us and then we consider moving, which gives us
kylie jue: And then we can just repeat that process over and over again. And really what we're looking for is we're looking for some path through the tree that allows us to have an English word at every step along the way.
kylie jue: For this example, we see that card is actually shrink a little word because we can shrink from heart to heart. We can shrink from our app, and then we can train from a and every single one of those things along the way is actually validate which word
kylie jue: And so we can actually find a path to the tree in three different ways. So this was the first time that we found, but you can actually find a second path as well.
kylie jue: But what's going to be interesting about this problem is rather than trying to find all possible paths are all possible ways of doing this, which we talked about before. And we're actually going to
kylie jue: only care about finding one and this is going to be our second category of Professor backtracking problems that we can solve, which is problems where we only care about either finding one solution or just proving that a solution exists.
kylie jue: And when we and then. So the last thing the last example that we need to look at is how do we know when something is actually not treatable. So the word cost is not well the reason why it's not drinkable.
kylie jue: Is so if you look at up the word up itself is not drinkable because neither P or you are words and the World Cup isn't drinkable because none of it's
kylie jue: Basically like sub sequences are words themselves are suitable words themselves. And then at the highest level clusters not attributable word because none of the possible options that we get when we remove a single, single letter are shrinking the words themselves.
kylie jue: And so let's think about how we can frame that in terms of base cases and recursive cases.
kylie jue: Obesity is is going to be, you know, if we encounter a word is not attributable word, then we know we've been stopped right away, right, that violates our definition. And then probably tells us, hey, there's nothing much more fruitful to explore and going down.
kylie jue: But if we encounter a single letter word that is treatable. That's a great base case, that means we've actually found something successful
kylie jue: And so with a with a single letter word. It's very easy to determine whether it's drinkable or not business, kind of, by definition, anything that is a valid language, English word
kylie jue: And as a single letter is going to be sure
kylie jue: But so then for the reverse of cases what we look at is
kylie jue: A multi letter word is going to be shrink of all. And if we can remove a letter to form a drinkable word. So if we can remove a single letter and then recursive we find something that is drinkable, then we know that we're good to go.
kylie jue: But it's going to be not drinkable. If no matter what we try or what letter and the word is not
kylie jue: One quick note before we jump into the code. And this idea of, we're going to introduce this new class bottle lexicon and lexicon is just a really helpful at that is kind of, you can think of it as a specialized set for storing specifically words.
kylie jue: Specifically strings of words and they offer even faster look up in a normal Cephas
kylie jue: That's kind of helpful because usually dictionaries like English dictionary or very large and store a lot of words.
kylie jue: Really the only thing you need to know about how to use them is they have a contained function just like sets it works exactly how stuff works.
kylie jue: And they also have a contains prefix function and which we're not going to talk about much today, but will become useful when you, when we talk about things on Monday.
kylie jue: Yeah. And so basically I need to know. It's kind of just like a specialized said it's just a little bit more efficient. And we usually use it for that.
kylie jue: Reason, there's a really good question in the chat about did we mean that a single letter word is not drinkable. Um, which is a really great distinction. Sorry.
kylie jue: A single letter word, by definition, is yes. Good question. You can no longer shrink it because it is like the baseline definition of a shrink of a word, but that's a good question.
kylie jue: Yeah. So yeah, so the answer is like if you were to give a function and say, like, is it drinkable. If it's an if it's a valid one letter word, the answer would be true. And that's, like, this is the smallest but still a word.
kylie jue: But you cannot go farther than oh one letter word. Um, yeah. So it's a little bit confusing, but yeah. So, we define it to be drinkable. If it's one letter, and it is a word.
kylie jue: Alright, so let's actually see
kylie jue: We actually are.
kylie jue: We say a word we mean like a valid word in the English dictionary or in a particular lexicon that we're going to provide you, that's what we say when we say word so like the letter K on its own would not be considered
kylie jue: A word that is shrinking, because that is not an actual word and it's one letter, but the letter A would be a drinkable word because it's one letter, and it is
kylie jue: About word
kylie jue: Okay, so I'm actually going to cheat a little bit. So I'm mostly just want to point out some key components of the code here and they're a little bit different than what we saw before.
kylie jue: Just because the technical stuff running a little bit low on time so you don't have time to do it all together. But I do want to point out kind of a couple of important things
kylie jue: So the first is that we have our basis, right, like we said our base case was defined by any word that was like one and was also which one
kylie jue: And then our recursive case was defined by basically looking at
kylie jue: Whether or not or basically making all the possible decisions which letter to remove from our string.
kylie jue: And so we will loop through all the letters we reduce our string by one by removing that letter, and then the key part that's different is what you see here.
kylie jue: The key part that's missing is what you see here, which is that what we say is if our
kylie jue: Word is evaluating what sport. Then we want to continue the reversion which makes sense, right, if, if our we remove a letter and we get to a word that's not an English word. It probably doesn't make sense to keep a person
kylie jue: But then the key difference is that we say we call a recursive function. And we know that it's been returnable in but basically tells us whether or not our reduced word was for the shrink about word in its own right.
kylie jue: And if we see that that is true. We actually return true right away.
kylie jue: And this is a kind of key component of solving problems where we only care about finding one solution or just proving that a solution exists.
kylie jue: Which is that as soon as we know that we found the solution or that a solution exists. We can we can we don't need to try anymore decisions. We don't need to flush out more of the decision tree. We can just say that we're done.
kylie jue: And and
kylie jue: That is, yeah, that is sort of the main difference. So when you move from problems that deal with a new meeting all possible solutions.
kylie jue: You're full of pitches always going to run. However, many times. It runs, you're always going to spawn off the same number of calls and not that
kylie jue: But when you move to the world of only caring about finding one solution or just seeing if a certain property folds or if you can just prove this single solution exists and you'll see this sort of pattern and a reverse of that.
kylie jue: And so
kylie jue: Just a another takeaway sort of from what we have to stop.
kylie jue: And notice that this was a number. Another example of copy of that recurs I didn't pointed out super closely, but no. Do you notice that our word is being passed by value again.
kylie jue: Which means that when we make this edited copy down here and edited copy only exists locally to a specific function called are suffering.
kylie jue: And in this problem, we were using backtracking to find a solution if it existed and the way that the recursive case was structured reflected that
kylie jue: And which basically told us that we try out as before we start to try out all options at each decision point and we may have to explore it a large portion of the decision tree in order to find solution.
kylie jue: But as soon as the recursive call returns true or tells us that something as possible, then we can cut off our iteration, we don't need to go any further, we know that we found a solution and we just passed that answer all the way back up.
kylie jue: And we only return false. We only know that our property, no longer holds if we looked at all possible options and nothing along the way. It was very fruitful.
kylie jue: And so that's sort of, again, another key component of how we think about the difference between finding all solutions versus just finding if one solution exists.
kylie jue: And there was a question in the chat is, was there a helper function for this one, or did we not need one. Yeah, that's a great question. Um, so in this one. Notice there's actually no helper function, we can directly define this function.
kylie jue: Sort of just straight up. And the reason why, if you remember
kylie jue: Anyway. And what you notice is that there's only one piece of information that
kylie jue: Needed to keep track and our recursive tree. So you go back to the decision tree every note in the decision tree actually only had one puzzle.
kylie jue: Piece of information. And so in this case we don't need a helper function because the the thing that we're trying to determine has the property is actually the only thing that we need to track over time because that word itself will just get smaller and smaller.
Yeah, good question.
kylie jue: Oh alright so quick announcements for today. And remember the grace period for summit to us tonight and we'll be releasing assignment three by the
kylie jue: End of the day and and the assignment three hour session will be tomorrow evening at 6pm and then we'll post the slides and recording afterwards, and I will also be releasing practice problems and some more information about the diagnostic over the weekend as well.
kylie jue: Cool. And so what I'm saying. The last part, and we are running a little bit over time because. So some of the technical issues, unfortunately.
kylie jue: And so what I'll say is I don't probably aim to go until 1225 and if you have to leave early. Feel free to leave it will be recorded. I would strongly recommend and coming check checking out the end of the lecture before
kylie jue: Starting on the assignment, but I will. I just want to give you a brief intro to this idea of success with will show up on the next slide.
kylie jue: So this idea of success is that, you know, given a group of people. And let's say we wanted to generate all possible teams.
kylie jue: And so you could think of another teaching team for this class of me having
kylie jue: What if we wanted to generate sort of the different possible teams that could show up.
kylie jue: And so let's think of a puzzle teams that could be well you could decided the kind of mean and take none of us. So even though this team seems kind of useless and it actually is still a subset. So the empty set is a subset of the original set of options that we had
kylie jue: And and. But as we're generating the subsets. It's probably easiest for us as humans to think about generating subsets of a particular size. And so you could have all teams of size one, or just just kind of your
kylie jue: You could have all team decides to so you can pick whichever pairs of us that you, you want to sort of work with or you can pick all of us right so that's also a valid team with all the options, who started off with you. Tell us. Okay. I actually want
kylie jue: And so this is again going to be another example of generating all solutions using recursive backtracking. We're going to try to find some recursive intuition in the way that the subsets are defined and then see if we can use backtracking agenda.
kylie jue: And so let's see if we can find a cabinet in these options and ideally we would like to have you sort of try this out on their own and breakout rooms, but we are running a little, a little low on time today.
kylie jue: For thinking about how a computer may generate these subsets. Let's look at an interesting pattern that we might see in these examples here. And what's interesting is happen exactly half of the subsets contain my name. So half of these teams can be
kylie jue: Half of these teams to contain Kylie and half of those teams contain trip. Okay. Kind of interesting observation.
kylie jue: But what another thing you notice is half of the things that contain trip also contain it.
kylie jue: And then half of the things that contain me and trip also contain highly
kylie jue: And so this idea like, oh, half of this possible solutions kind of break down to the point where does that
kylie jue: Why is that important.
kylie jue: Let's say my home. You might define us in terms of decision tree.
kylie jue: So we're gonna have a decision at each step.
kylie jue: And the idea is
kylie jue: We're going to just decide do we include this element in the set, or do we not right with these two possible options right
kylie jue: So we have these two options of including an element or not including the element in the final subset will always generate half the solutions that don't have this person.
kylie jue: And half of the solutions that do and if we repeatedly make this decision actually over and over again for every person and for every combination we will actually generate all possible subsets.
kylie jue: And again, the last important piece of info. The last sort of subset of things that need to think about when we're dealing with
kylie jue: Brokers of backtracking is the information we need to store along the way. In this case, similar to how we have a permutations. We wanted to store the set that we built so far as long as, in addition to the remaining elements that we have from our operational set
kylie jue: And so let's see what the decision tree mega pack and so will always, you know, as we always do with these types of problems. We start off with the empty set. And then we asked ourselves a first question of do we include Nick are doing it.
kylie jue: Well, we include me, we see that our subset that we're keeping track of contains me
kylie jue: On the right hand side. Now that we've made that decision, we can ask the question of do we include Kylie, or do we not include Kylie so that generates a note that just has me versus the know that has booked me entirely
kylie jue: And then we ask ourselves doing good trip so we either have a branch that doesn't include trip and woman that's
kylie jue: And then if we go back to our other branch. We can again ask ourselves the question of for the case where we chose Nick, but not Kyrie during the trip or do we not include
kylie jue: And then we can repeat this process on the left hand side right at every point in time, you're picking one person. So at the first level. It was Nick at the second level. It was Kylie and with the third level, it was
kylie jue: So you're always picking one person and then you're asking yourself the question of, do I include this person or
kylie jue: This person and what's kind of magical is what we see in this tree that combination of questions allows us to generate all possible subsets. By the time we've reached the bottom of the tree.
kylie jue: And so we pointed out, this idea that we need to keep track of the remaining elements in the original set and and we kind of asked ourselves, well, why is this important
kylie jue: So that way. Yeah.
kylie jue: Okay.
kylie jue: Anyway, sorry, I'm gonna try to try to fight through this for the last couple minutes. There's, there's so many things going on right now.
kylie jue: Okay, so
kylie jue: What we basically see here is that
kylie jue: At the first step we had three options. I mean, we got can either choose make we could choose Kylie or the truth.
kylie jue: And after we made our first set of decisions which was whether or not
kylie jue: We only had two options for me. I'm just hearing the truth Pilar to choose trip. After we made the decision about whether or not to quickly than we just have one option or meeting because the option of choosing to do what to what to do about it.
kylie jue: And then at the very end, after we've actually built the first upsets the way that we knew that we were done is we ask ourselves the question of include or not include about every single person that was originally there.
kylie jue: And so by the time we get to the end. We actually don't have the option slot.
kylie jue: And so then our base case in this case would be, you know, people remaining like to choose from.
kylie jue: And then our records the case in this case would be picking someone in the set and then choosing to include them or not include them.
kylie jue: And so notice in this case, actually, we're actually back to a fixed number of branches and instead we always have two choices. And we always have to reverse of calls and one of them corresponds to INCLUDING THE PERSON AND ONE OF THEM corresponds to excellent person.
kylie jue: And so again I will post sort of the quarter component of the solution and in the starter code after lecture and and I really encourage you checking out this code.
kylie jue: Before the lecture on Monday and next week because it actually has an interesting structure.
kylie jue: A slightly more explicit way of doing choose explore and choose and we'll, we'll start off with today's lecture. I'm actually going to talk to me about that and walking through the code for this subsets problem.
kylie jue: And sort of seeing how it is different now that we're dealing with sex, sexual access the data structure, rather than
kylie jue: String. So the strings. We could pass by value, but the sex. We're going to be working with her purse and functions that passed them by reference. And so it's going to be kind of a critical difference in how we frame our case.
kylie jue: Based off of that, but I believe that is the end point for today, since we're already running
kylie jue: A couple minutes over, and as always feel free to stick around and let us know if you have questions, and then. Best of luck getting started on the assignment.
kylie jue: And we've covered almost everything you need to know for the assignment and you'll be able to do about the first like 80% of it before Monday's lecture and then we'll cover the last component of what you need to know on Monday.
kylie jue: Who alright so thanks everyone for coming and for sticking with us through all the sections and and
kylie jue: We can
Evan F Davis: You. Thank you.
Thank you.
Arul Saxena: Thank you.
Oz Gitelson: Thank you.
Nick Bowman: Okay.
kylie jue: Yeah.
Nick Bowman: Okay, well,
Nick Bowman: If you have questions, feel free to ask them if you can't hear me. Just let me know and I'll switch back to using my computer.
Nick Bowman: And
edouard des: I actually would have a question.
edouard des: If we when we did the word thing with the with the choices for each step of the word, essentially, if we can look at it that way. I don't know if we should but
edouard des: Like if we if we took them and essentially did the word factorial, right, because we were every time we would, it would kind of do the same thing. It was like the factorial function, but
edouard des: For a word.
edouard des: Because like every, every subsequent iteration of the tree was
Nick Bowman: Yeah, so we mean when we were generating permutations
edouard des: Yeah, when we're sending permutations
Nick Bowman: Yeah yeah i mean i think that's that's that's certainly one way to think about it, where
Nick Bowman: Like, and that is why there's kind of an intrinsic relationship between like factorial, the numerical expression which tells you, sort of, Okay, first you had six options.
Nick Bowman: Then you had five options then you had four, then you have three then you had to then you have one. So the, the total amount of things that you had there right it was related
Nick Bowman: To to the fact, like the mathematical factorial function but yes permutations. When order matters right is is when like you can use the factorial to sort of represent
Nick Bowman: How many total options that you have. I mean, yeah, we were basically you know I wouldn't say we were generating the word factorial because factorial is like specifically defined for numbers.
Nick Bowman: Like it is like a mathematical thing that explains numbers.
Nick Bowman: But this idea of permutations can apply to many different things, right. So we did it with strings like we did with characters have a string. You could also do the words of the stream. You could do it with
Nick Bowman: Arbitrary elements you do with people. Right. Like you can you can do all the permutations operation can apply on many different types of data. Yeah, and the relationship between factorial and permutations. There is that there are n factorial from mutations of a word based on answers.
Yeah.
Nick Bowman: Kind of this, you have your hand up.
Kenneth Fischer: So you mentioned during the lecture that you'd be releasing notes on the diagnostic and practice problems. Um, when are you planning on doing that. I don't know if there's an election I missed it, or
Nick Bowman: No, I must be doing it at some point over the weekend probably later in the weekend.
Nick Bowman: The i mean the the important sort of things that you need to know or posted at the beginning of the quarter or like like just for planning when you're going to take it and so it'll just be to be released over the span of Friday, Saturday, Sunday, and next week.
Nick Bowman: It'll be designed to take one hour and you will have three hours to do it. And so there's not there's not meant to be any time pressure
Nick Bowman: So if you want. You're welcome to allocate like any three hour block in that time. Pretty much you can take it and you can expect it like our goal we design it to spend about an hour.
Nick Bowman: And the details. We're gonna post over the return will just be more of like logistical things like how do you download it and how do you open it and how do you run it and like what types of problems.
Kenneth Fischer: I see. Thank you.
Nick Bowman: Yep. First
Nick Bowman: And I did you have a question.
Aadi M Rane: So for the problems, how to actually come up with the tree. Like, how do you have to
Aadi M Rane: Like this is a decision. I want to
Aadi M Rane: Make this is what I want sources such as common practice.
Nick Bowman: And I think it'll, it'll certainly come a lot more practice time notice right like before we ever drew the trees. Right. Um, one thing that I want to point out right is
Nick Bowman: Yeah, so, so notice before we started drawing the decision tree right we always ask ourselves these three questions, which is, you know, what is the decision.
Nick Bowman: Making step.
Nick Bowman: And what are the options that we have at
Aadi M Rane: Each step.
Nick Bowman: And then what is the information we need to store. And so I think your question is sort of like, well, how do you even answer these questions and in sort of like obviously that'll be specific to the problem and something that I think as you get more practice with
Nick Bowman: Different parameters of backtracking problems.
Nick Bowman: Will
Nick Bowman: Sort of come a little bit more
Nick Bowman: Like well for just come more naturally. But what I would say is the way that we got ourselves to being able to answer these questions.
Nick Bowman: Right as we work through examples right like we started off, we said, all right, we wanted to find all possible subsets of may Kylie and trip and and we did that right and we found all the subsets and we basically asked ourselves, like can we find a pattern.
Nick Bowman: In the subsets. Right.
Nick Bowman: And by finding the pattern in the subsets.
Nick Bowman: We were able to get a better intuition of, like, Okay, what are we actually deciding upon every point along the way as we generate these subsets. Right.
Nick Bowman: And for subsets itself. The patterns, a little bit vague right like it's not entirely clear how this pattern of like
Nick Bowman: Oh well, half the things contain this thing and half of them don't like translating that to a decision is not super clear right and so like if that part kind of came out of nowhere. That's like, that's totally fine. Like it is actually not super intuitive why you would frame it that
Nick Bowman: Way. Um, but maybe maybe a better way to think about would be of permutations right we generated all the permutations. And we were like, oh, wow, like quarter of them start with this letter and then like all all possible letters could
Aadi M Rane: Act as starting letters.
Nick Bowman: And then within each of those ones that start with a certain letter. If I look at what's left. It's just permutations of their meeting letters. Right. And so with that, it's a little bit easier to see this recursive insight of, like, okay, all I need to do is just decide which
Nick Bowman: Letter comes first.
Nick Bowman: And after I've decided which letter comes first, then I can
Nick Bowman: My recursion will generate all the remaining
Nick Bowman: And then, then you can go into. Oh, well, how do I know which options I have for the letter that goes first, and things like that. And so I would always recommend sort of your problem solving process on
Nick Bowman: These to
Nick Bowman: Start with the examples. Look for patterns and how you generated the examples and then let that try to motivate how you to find what your decisions are and what your options are at each step and then after you've done all that, can you
Nick Bowman: Draw the decision tree.
Nick Bowman: And now you've done all this work, and you're like, Oh man, I have to write the code now.
Nick Bowman: Time, you've done all that thinking writing the code actually will again will take practice but writing the code will sort of flow we
Said,
Nick Bowman: Thank you. I think what you said. Okay.
Aadi M Rane: We and water. Like, what are the options like mean like it are the options like when you're asking those questions. This options like
Aadi M Rane: What decisions enemy.
Aadi M Rane: That point
kylie jue: Um, it's, yeah. So, so when you think about a decision point being a note in your tree.
kylie jue: The options are sort of at that decision point, what can I pick from. Right. So in this case, when our decision was
kylie jue: Are we going to include someone or not the only options or yes or no right versus what the permutations problem you have
kylie jue: What letter, am I going to put at that point. And it's all the remaining letters that you haven't yet put in the word. Um, another tip I will give to and just reiterating that this is difficult, like figuring out these decision trees is not something that is
kylie jue: Always initially intuitive to folks.
kylie jue: And that's why we're giving you these example problems that can potentially show you different ways of thinking about trees.
kylie jue: But another thing that will be helpful is also thinking about what is it that I want to output. And that's why we're specifically showing you permutations and subsets. It's sort of like
kylie jue: are we generating permutations of our input, are we generating subsets.
kylie jue: And again, it's not going to be fail proof and it won't be like you can't just fit every problem two subsets or permutations, either.
kylie jue: But sometimes, that'll help you with thinking about, okay, then I should be thinking about the decisions at each step in this way. Um, but depending on what my output is going to be
kylie jue: And then I saw Debbie's hands.
Demi Lei: But yeah, so one. I'm not sure if that's like a good question, but like, so for the permutation one arm.
Demi Lei: Like we do the same thing of like they're repeating letters.
Demi Lei: In the word like when we do the same thing and how we do it.
kylie jue: Yeah, that's a good question. It's actually a matter if you have permutations with like a word with the same letter, right, because then the actual string that you're pulling them out from to say, I've already picked them.
kylie jue: It'll just be in there twice. Right. Like if I pick a word like people that has to ease in it. The first time I include an E I remove one of the ease. But the other is still there.
kylie jue: So there's still the process remains the same and it won't confuse the computer. Yeah, so that's an important distinction to between sets up sets and like the permutations problem you can do as long as you're keeping track of the elements themselves.
Demi Lei: Sorry. So I was trying to say like with like permutation like. So how do we do it though, if we need to find different permutations will
kylie jue: Actually be the same, like if you right now. I
kylie jue: Just takes in a string right and removes characters and almost you could think about, like, without even worrying about what the actual character itself is all the characters are in there because
kylie jue: I'm trying to decide if I want to say by index or not, but not exact, but because your string right you have your taking out a specific character.
kylie jue: The remaining in the chosen. Are those the names of the remaining and so far.
kylie jue: The process is the same in you want to pull up the code and might be. Yeah. Just show
kylie jue: Right. You're no matter what string was passed in as I'm that you are making a permutation of, um, it doesn't like nothing in here is saying like
kylie jue: Only like pull out all instance of that letter or a black character right it is just pulling out the index the particular index that you're looping through. So for example, if your length was six.
kylie jue: And both characters, two and four. He it'll still only pull out one of these right so it. Yeah, it still works the same.
Demi Lei: Oh, yeah. Oh, okay. I guess my question was like you know like how do we reduce the repetition, or like, can we do it within this recursive process or do we just have to do something sort of at the end like make a set and shove everything in
kylie jue: Yeah, no. You just, you just maintain a set. So, so you're right that if there are duplicate letters in the input, you will get some permutation that look exactly the same.
kylie jue: And if you're just yes, you will see that voice. So the only way to eliminate that is. Yeah. Like, you have to store them on a set, basically, we're just have a way of knowing which ones you before.
kylie jue: Yeah, so like you, if you, if you care about not having those duplicates, or I guess. Yeah, they're effectively duplicates, because they look exactly the same. The only way to get rid of that would be to
Demi Lei: Okay, I got it. Any other question I have is that so so for the subset problems that we were looking at. Um, can I kind of just view it as like
Demi Lei: Because that reminds me of the coin flipping problems that we looked at. Yesterday, I think. And like the picking. Yes. And now it's kind of like head and tail.
Demi Lei: So in that case, are they kind of like the same like picking three people were like picking three
Demi Lei: Houses, they're generating all set of a set that has three elements in there. It's kind of like flipping three coins and I let's say head would be like, we want to include this until would be like, we don't want to include this so like
Demi Lei: Yeah, they kind of
sameness.
kylie jue: Yeah, I mean, basically.
kylie jue: The way it's a little bit different is like when you're flipping heads and tails both ended up in your sequence right so
Demi Lei: Yeah, the sequence.
kylie jue: And and in this case, like in our subsets. If we flip. If we call tales of the like not include case.
Demi Lei: Like
kylie jue: That doesn't actually like show up in our set right it kind of is like in the absence of it, I guess. But yeah, I mean that's effectively yes you your, you can think of the yes no decision is just a coin flip. At each
Demi Lei: Branch right
kylie jue: Like am I going to include this thing or my knocking.
kylie jue: And but the difference in the answers that you get comes from the fact that with the coins, regardless of what your flip you include like you literally included that value in your answer. Whereas look specifically for the subset veneration like
kylie jue: The flipping of the coin determines whether or not that element gets added or not.
kylie jue: But, but the thing that I would say is different though to be careful of is with the point sequences problem.
kylie jue: Re you actually know yeah i think i think that's that's
Demi Lei: Okay, I got it. I got. Thank you.
Yeah.
Eshani Jha: Oh yeah, I actually had a question about our homework assignments. I'm not sure if this is the right place to ask it, but I was just wondering for the extensions are we supposed to run test cases on those two
Eshani Jha: Like
Eshani Jha: Minor own student test cases.
kylie jue: Yeah, I mean, it's up to you, right, like, at that point, like you're kind of just designing something interesting like extra that you want to put together.
kylie jue: And like we have a very loose very very good set of requirements for extensions, just because it's like, all right, you know, you're choosing to do something on your own. So you kind of have agency or on what you're doing. So, and
kylie jue: I think we would hope that you do because we think that it's an important part of like a great development process but you know it's it's your extension. So you're more than welcome to suffer.
kylie jue: And then the test there to is you also don't want to write an extension that's going to break the actual original functionality of the main part of the program.
Eshani Jha: That's the main reason you might want to write test. Yeah.
Eshani Jha: Yeah, so I actually, I actually wrote test, but I wasn't sure if I was supposed to or not. So I was just double check. Thank you.
Yeah.
edouard des: Massive question about the, about the Simon as well.
Sure.
edouard des: And if we if we like the short answers dot txt file. If we like put it as a PDF is that fine or is it preferable if it's a txt
kylie jue: No, don't put them in a PDF, because the the grading site that we use can't directly display the contents of a PDF
edouard des: So if, if I have it as it takes to have it as a PDF. Should I resubmit everything with it as a as a txt yeah
kylie jue: I'm in this case, it's fine. I would just tell your section here there they'll actually have to like download it and like opening
edouard des: Okay, most, most section leaders, look at it just via via the website.
kylie jue: You don't. Yeah, because the grading the files and the grading are done.
kylie jue: On the same website. So, yeah. So, and then they like, they can't like leave comments on a PDF, but they can, like,
Yeah.
kylie jue: So yeah, this time it's fine. I wouldn't worry about it. Just like let your section leader know
kylie jue: That they know that you're actually submitted them and they know where to look. Because they if it's not in that place. They may dismiss it.
kylie jue: And then in the future. I would just, I would just submit that text file. And if you need to submit like multimedia resources like because you grab something you can always include like individual screenshots in the in the folder that you submit and then make it
edouard des: But
kylie jue: Yeah, but for the answers themselves would be great if there
edouard des: I see. Okay. Okay. Thank you.
kylie jue: Any other questions.
kylie jue: Alright, well thanks for sticking around and hope you have a good weekend.
Demi Lei: All right. Thank you.